<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The East-India trade being lately proposed by a paper in print to be carryed on by a stock of 1400000. to be took up at interest on the credit of it self, ...</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1694</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A82395</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing E104</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224982</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99897421</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99897421</idno>
            <idno type="VID">132868</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A82395)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 132868)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2496:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The East-India trade being lately proposed by a paper in print to be carryed on by a stock of 1400000. to be took up at interest on the credit of it self, ...</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693/4]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title from caption and opening words of text.</note>
                  <note>Dated at end: January 3d. 1693/4.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>East India Company --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Commerce --  East Indies --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Sarah Wingo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-05</date>
            <label>Sarah Wingo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:132868:1"/>
            <head>The Eaſt-India TRADE</head>
            <p>BEING lately Propoſed by a Paper in Print to be carryed on by a Stock of 1400000 <hi>l.</hi> to be took up at Intereſt on the Credit of it ſelf, and upon one Months Tax of 70000 <hi>l.</hi> to be ſettled for ever to Anſwer the Intereſt of ſo much of that Money as the Produce of that Trade ſhould at any time fail to afford, (which without a mighty Misfortune can be none) and the Profit after to Redound to the Landed Men of the Kingdom proportionable to their Reſpective Intereſt (as more at large by that Paper appears) ſeeming very hard upon Merchants, and ſuch as only have Money, and ſo by that Propoſal can come to have no Advantage from that Trade, of the Benefit of which all <hi>England</hi> ought to partake: It ſeems much more Reaſonable it ſhould be divided between the Owners of Money and Land, which may be done thus.</p>
            <p>Suppoſe as aforeſaid the Stock for this Trade 1400000 <hi>l.</hi> to be took up at Intereſt as need ſhall require, and the Stock it ſelf, and one Months Tax of 70000 <hi>l. per</hi> Month for ever to be ſettled to ſecure it, which Security as aforeſaid, and a Committee to Manage (as in the Paper propoſed) being ſettled, let Books for Subſcriptions be opened, and let 700000 <hi>l.</hi> of the 1400000 <hi>l.</hi> Stock be Subſcribed in the very ſame way as other Stocks are Subſcribed for, and ſo to always remain one half of that 1400000 <hi>l.</hi> Stock, with this for Ever Advantage above the other half of it, <hi>viz.</hi> out of the Profits ariſing by the Trade 35000 <hi>l.</hi> which is 5 <hi>per Cent.</hi> Yearly for the 700000 <hi>l.</hi> Subſcribed, to be always paid in the firſt place to whoever ſhall be the Owners of the ſaid 700000 <hi>l.</hi> firſt Subſcribed. And after payment of that Intereſt, and the Intereſt of ſuch other Money (if any) as ſhall more be took up for the Uſe of the Company, is paid.</p>
            <p>The remaining Profits to be divided as upon a Stock of 1400000 <hi>l.</hi> the one Moyety to thoſe that Subſcribed the 700000 <hi>l.</hi> and the other Moyety to the Landed Men of the Kingdom, to each according to their Reſpective Intereſts. And if no Dividend be made till 30 <hi>per Cent.</hi> may be divided, ſuch Dividend on 1400000 <hi>l.</hi> ſtock will amount to 420000 <hi>l.</hi> whereof 210000 <hi>l.</hi> will anſwer and pay a three Months Tax, after the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:132868:2" rendition="simple:additions"/> Rate of 70000 <hi>l. per</hi> Month, to be paid to the Sheriff, and by the Sheriff to the Hundred, and thence to the Pariſh, and there to every Owner of Land, as his Proportion there ſtands. And the other 210000 <hi>l.</hi> will anſwer and pay to every Subſcriber 30 alſo <hi>per Cent.</hi> for his Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney Subſcribed, in the very ſame manner as Dividends in the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company have been at any time heretofore made.</p>
            <p>And thus this may be ſettled betwixt the Merchants, who furniſh the Money, and the Landed Men, who lay down no Money, and who for half the Profit of the whole Trade do ſecure it.</p>
            <p>This way brings in as much freſh Money to carry on the Trade as is now ta<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>'d of to be Subſcribed in, and will be ſecure (paſt all diſpute) to whoever Subſcribes it, as far as 5 <hi>per Cent.</hi> always, beſides one Moy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ety of all other Profit to be reaſonably hoped from the Trade.</p>
            <p>This from time to time lets in all ſuch as will buy themſelves in, and removes the Mighty Objection againſt the other Propoſals, That Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants would be by it left out. And when any other Objection (that ſeems to have weight) ſhall further be raiſed, it may be probably an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered, and by the Propoſer of this, who you ſee is deſirous that ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing at leaſt for the General Good ſhould at this time be done in this Thing.</p>
            <p>And Gentlemen are deſired to take Notice, That in the late Charters from the Crown to the Company (which is the only now Title they have to inſiſt on) Power is thereby reſerved to Their Majeſties to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termine thoſe Charters at any time before <hi>Michaelmas</hi> 1694. if ſo be that Their Majeſties in their Princely Wiſdom ſhall ſo pleaſe to think fit. So that whatever Alterations relating to the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Trade, His Majeſty by Act of Parliament or otherwiſe, ſhall pleaſe to make before <hi>Michael<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mas</hi> 1694. may be made before that time without any Injuſtice or true colour for Clamour; whereas after that time no Alterations in thoſe Charters can be made without juſt Reaſon for both for One and Twenty Years forward to come.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <date>
                     <hi>January</hi> 3<hi>
                        <hi rend="sup">d</hi>.</hi> 1693 / 4.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
